

A DETAIL-OBSESSED DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER WITH A PASSION FOR CREATING BEAUTIFUL, FUNCTIONAL, PIXEL-PERFECT BRAINCHILDREN

With more than 16 years of professional experience in graphic design and web development, I am deliberate about designing *invisible* user interfaces and writing clean, reusable code. I lean on my extensive design training along with my diverse programming industry knowledge to inform my decisions, making me a valuable asset to any team. I'm equally comfortable in both front end development roles and design roles.

EDUCATION

Watkins College of Art, Design, and Film-BFA in Graphic Design, 2006

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

User Experience Design
User Interface Design

Web Design & Development

Application Design & Development

Graphic Design
Information Architecture

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY/TECHNICAL SKILL LEVEL

HTML (Jade/Pug)
CSS (LESS, SASS, Stylus)
Javascript (JSX, JQuery, REACT)
PHP (Wordpress, CMS integration)
Structured Data Systems ————————————————————————————————————
Agile Development Practices
Front End Frameworks (Bootstrap, Bourbon, Neat, etc.)
Version Control (Github, Bitbucket)
Adobe Creative Suite
Sketch, UXPin, Invision
MAMP, CodeKit
Webpack, NPM
Database (MongoDB, SQL)



RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Designer & Developer, Nashville, TN

2004 - present

With clients ranging from an Alaskan fishing lodge to a tuba museum, I focus on creating fluidly responsive websites and collateral that follow industry standards and best practices and are optimized for practical, user-focused solutions.

PHY (formerly BKON Connect), Nashville, TN

Developer / 2016 - 2018

PHY was a SaaS company managing QR codes, NFC tags, and IoT beacons on the Physical Web. In an agile/scrum environment, I was part of a specialized team that deployed new features on a weekly schedule. As the front end developer responsible for translating design ideas into jsx components within the MERN (Mongo-Express-React-Node) stack, I integrated those components with the web application, PHY.net, and fixed bugs.

Drive Social Media, Nashville, TN

Web Developer / 2015 - 2016

Although primarily focused on social media presence management, Drive also offered custom Wordpress websites. During my tenure as the web developer, I designed and developed custom websites, managed client communications and edits, and gave new Wordpress users individual training on site features. I updated the development workflow, along with creating a three-tiered SEO package now available in all office branches.

iDESIGN, INC. (purchased by Phase 3 in 2014), Nashville, TN

Web Developer / 2013 - 2015

As one of three front end developers, I integrated custom website designs into the in-house CMS. I introduced the practice of using GitHub repositories and LESS with code compilers, creating consistency across the agency within the company's LAMP (Linux-Apache-MySQL-PHP) stack. I implemented baseline SEO standards, including Twitter Cards, Open Graph, and Schema.org structured data.

cj ADVERTISING, Nashville, TN

Web Developer / 2011 - 2013

cjAdvertising is a one-stop shop for personal injury lawyers' multimedia needs. Hired as an entry-level junior designer, I was promoted to web developer, where I handled website maintenance and updates for more than 40 clients across the country. I assisted with development of the internal project management system, which housed several hundred projects and was accessed by approximately 150 employees and clients. I received multiple nods for outstanding service, including both peer-nominated honors and Employee of the Month, awarded by company leadership.